Finding Aid for the Allen Sigel Collection of Scores, 1946-1998
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Compositions, 1946-1998, I.; Folder 1-85
  - Sigel, Allen Poe potpurri, voice and piano Alone; The haunted palace; A dream within a dream: for voice and piano, 1993, 1 manuscript score (8, 15, 7 p.); Holograph (Ink and pencil) Words by Edgar Allan Poe. First line of text for Alone: From childhood's hour I have not been as others were; I have not seen as others saw; I could not bring my passions from a common spring. First line of text for The haunted palace: In the greenest of our valleys by good angels tenanted, once a fair and stately palace-radiant palace- reared its head. First line of text for A dream within a dream: Take this kiss upon the brow, and in parting from you now, this much let me avow-you are not wrong who deem that my days have been a dream. Includes an additional photocopy of The haunted palace. The haunted palace and A dream within a dream are versions of the movements with same titles in Sigel's Poe potpurri for narrator, trumpet, and saxophone quartet. (Box 07, Folder 062)
  - Sigel, Allen Poe potpurri, voice and piano. Selections Alone; A dream within a dream, 1993, 1 manuscript score (7, 7 p.); Holograph (Pencil) Words by Edgar Allan Poe. A dream within a dream is a different version of the movement with the same title in Sigel's Poe potpurri for narrator, trumpet, and saxophone quartet. (Box 07, Folder 063)
    Contents: Alone--A dream within a dream.
  - Sigel, Allen Poe potpurri, voice and piano. Haunted palace The haunted palace: for voice and piano, 1993, 1 score (15 p.); Computer-notated score. Words by Edgar Allan Poe. Version of movement with the same title in Sigel's Poe Potpurri for narrator, trumpet, and saxophone quartet. (Box 07, Folder 064)
  - Sigel, Allen Poe potpurri. Dream within a dream A dream within a dream, undated, 1 manuscript score (7 p.); Holograph (Pencil) Sketch with instrumentation not noted; scored as solo line with piano accompaniment. Part of his work, Poe potpurri [sic]. (Box 07, Folder 065)
  - Sigel, Allen Poe potpurri, Haunted palace The haunted palace, undated, 1 manuscript score (14 p.); Holograph (Pencil) with text written in red pencil. Sketch for voice (sung), flute, oboe, clarinet, horn, and bassoon. (Box 07, Folder 066)
  - Sigel, Allen Prelude and allegro Prelude and allegro for mixed clarinet quartet, 1994, 2 scores (12 p.) and 4 manuscript parts; Arranged for B? clarinet 1, 2, 3, and bass. 1 ink manuscript and 1 computer-generated score, accompanied by a marked photocopy of holograph of the Allegro, which was titled Homage to Prokofiev. Also includes 4 holograph (ink) parts. (Box 07, Folder 067)
  - Sigel, Allen Quintet, winds Quintet for wind instruments, undated, 1 manuscript score (17 p.); Holograph (Ink) For flute, clarinet, oboe, horn, and bassoon. (Box 07, Folder 068)
  - Sigel, Allen Serenade and rondo Serenade and rondo for B? clarinet and orchestra, undated, 1 manuscript score (45 p.); Holograph (Pencil and ink) (Box 07, Folder 069)
  - Sigel, Allen Shtetl echoes Shtetl echoes for saxophone quartet, October 1995, 2 manuscript scores (13 p.); Holograph (Ink) score and spiral-bound photocopy of holograph with additional markings. (Box 07, Folder 070)
  - Sigel, Allen Shtetl echoes Shtetl echoes, 1995, 1 manuscript score (15 p.); Holograph (Pencil) sketch version. (Box 07, Folder 071)
  - Sigel, Allen Shtetl echoes Shtetl echoes for saxophone quartet, 1995, 1 score (21 p.); Computer-notated score. Accompanied with a manuscript note from Sigel to "Steve" about the copying and a photocopy of a typescript (1 leaf) program note. (Box 07, Folder 072)
  - Sigel, Allen Shtetl echoes Shtetl echoes for saxophone quartet (parts), 1995, 4 parts (5 p. ea.); Computer-notated parts with additional editorial markings. (Box 07, Folder 073)
  - Sigel, Allen Sonata, violin, piano [Sonata for violin and piano], undated, 1 manuscript score (27 p.); Holograph (Ink and Pencil) The completion of the 3rd movement is in a spiral-bound music manuscript book that also contains a sketch for a woodwind quintet and an arrangement of Beethoven's String quartet in G major op. 18 no. 2, 3rd movement, 1st theme for woodwind quintet. (Box 08, Folder 074)
  - Sigel, Allen Sonata, violin, piano Sonata for violin and piano, undated, 1 manuscript part (8 p.); Holograph (Pencil) violin part. (Box 08, Folder 075)
  - Sigel, Allen Songs of summer Songs of summer for mixed chorus and clarinet, Summer 1992, 2 manuscript scores (21 p. each) and 1 manuscript part (4 p.); Holograph (Ink) and photocopy; holograph part is for clarinet. For Harriet Simons and the University at Buffalo Choir. First lines of texts: Pastorale. Caressing breezes glide past; The beach. Seen from the high bridge it sparkles; All life must yield. This cycle, dimly felt in our youth. Text is unattributed, presumably by Sigel. Accompanied by photocopied typescript (2 p. ) containing the lyrics. (Box 08, Folder 076)
    Contents: Pastorale--The beach--All life must yield.
  - Sigel, Allen Songs of summer [Songs of summer. Sketches], Summer 1992, 1 manuscript score (15 p.) and 1 manuscript part (2 p.); Holograph (Pencil) sketch version of score and clarinet part. Clarinet part also includes other sketches, including Sigel's work Patriots all of 1992. (Box 08, Folder 077)
    Contents: Pastorale--The beach(begins on p. 4 without title)--Summer's end (titled All life must yield in final version).
  - Sigel, Allen Songs of summer Songs of summer for chorus and clarinet, Summer 1992, 1 part (5 p.); Computer-notated part. (Box 08, Folder 078)
  - Sigel, Allen Swing set Swing set for saxophone quartet, undated, 2 manuscript scores; Accompanied with a description of the piece. Arranged for soprano, alto, tenor, and baritone saxophone. Includes 1 spiral-bound holograph (photocopy) of all movements, and 1 holograph (photocopy) of the 2nd movement. (Box 08, Folder 079)
    Contents: Overture--Swing finale.
  - Sigel, Allen Trio, flute, clarinet, bassoon Trio [for] flute, clarinet, bassoon, March 1946, 1 manuscript score (14 p.) and 3 manuscript parts; Holograph (Ink) (Box 08, Folder 080)
    Contents: Prelude--Finale.
  - Sigel, Allen U.B., our university: Alma mater, 1991, 1 manuscript score (2 p.); Holograph (Ink) For unaccompanied four-voice chorus (soprano, alto, tenor, bass). Words by Allen Sigel. First line of text: Learning's clear light shines radiant and bright. Accompanied by printed lyrics (1 leaf) bearing the title U. B., our university. (Box 08, Folder 081)
  - Sigel, Allen U. B., our university Alma mater, State University of New York at Buffalo, 1991, 4 scores (3 p. each); Computer-notated score for chorus (soprano, alto, tenor, bass) and piano accompaniment. Words by Allen Sigel. First line of text: Learning's clear light shines radiant and bright. Scores numbered 1-4; number 4 has the title U. B., our university; number 3 has the first line of text from Sigel's work, Patriots all. (Box 08, Folder 082)
  - Sigel, Allen U. B., our university Alma mater, State University of New York at Buffalo, 1991, 2 scores; Computer-notated score for unaccompanied 4-voice chorus. Words by Allen Sigel. First line of text: Learning's clear light shines radiant and bright. Accompanied by the printed lyrics (1 leaf) bearing the title U. B., our university. The two scores differ in formatting and contain minor variations in lyrics. (Box 08, Folder 083)
  - Sigel, Allen U. B., our university U. B., our university, 1991, 2 leaves of music; Holograph (Ink) and computer-notated. Single melody line with text. Words by Allen Sigel. First line of text: Learning's clear light shines radiant and bright, in this noble university. (Box 08, Folder 084)
  - Sigel, Allen U. B., our university; arr. U. B., our university, 1991, 1 manuscript score (5 p.); Holograph (Photocopy) The work is for chorus and band; this score is only for band. Words (not included here) by Allen Sigel. (Box 09, Folder 085)
- Arrangements of works by other composers, 1972-1991, II.; Folder 86-98
  Arranged alphabetically by composer surname and then by uniform title.
  - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 Quartets, piano, strings, no. 1, op. 25, G minor. Rondo alla zingarese; arr. Quartet for piano, oboe, clarinet, and violoncello, op. 25. Rondo alla zingarese, undated, 1 manuscript score (15 p.) and 3 parts; The score is a pencil holograph. The piano and violoncello lines in the score are photocopies from a printed score taped onto the holograph. The clarinet part is an ink holograph; the oboe part is a photocopy of a holograph, the violoncello part is a photocopy of a printed part with some changes on manuscript paper taped onto the part. Also includes photocopy of a printed violin part. (Box 09, Folder 086)
  - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 Ungarische Tänze. Selections; arr. Hungarian dances 1, 3, 4, 5, undated, 1 manuscript score (23 p.) and 5 manuscript parts; Holograph (Pencil) Originally for piano; arranged for woodwind quintet. Each dance is a separate fascicle in score and parts. (Box 09, Folder 087)
  - Confrey, Zez, 1895-1971 Dizzy fingers; arr. Dizzy fingers (1923), undated, 1 manuscript score (11 p.) and 5 manuscript parts; Holograph (Pencil) Arranged for woodwind quintet. (Box 09, Folder 088)
  - Confrey, Zez, 1895-1971 Dizzy fingers; arr. Dizzy fingers (1923), undated, 1 manuscript score (8 p.); Holograph (Pencil) Incomplete draft. (Box 09, Folder 089)
  - Devienne, François, 1759-1803 Deuxième sonate pour clarinette si? et piano-forte Sonatas, clarinet, continuo, no. 2, op. 28, 1972, 1 score; Clarinet part annotated by Allen Sigel, including an additional leaf (ink holograph) containing a composed cadenza. (Box 09, Folder 090)
  - Ellington, Duke, 1899-1974 Paris blues; arr. Paris Blues (1961), undated, 1 manuscript score (11 p.) and 5 manuscript parts; Holograph (Pencil) Arranged for woodwind quintet. (Box 09, Folder 091)
  - Ellington, Duke, 1899-1974 Selections; arr. A Duke Ellington triptych, undated, 1 manuscript score and 5 manuscript parts; Holograph (Pencil) Arranged for woodwind quintet by Allen Sigel. There are duplicate manuscript parts for the flute in Caravan, and flute and clarinet in Sophisticated lady. (Box 09, Folder 092)
    Contents: Caravan--Sophisticated lady--Take the A train.
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759 Fugues, organ, HMV 609, A minor; arr. Fugue number 5 in A minor for soprano voice, clarinet, and piano, undated, 1 manuscript score (7 p.) and 2 manuscript parts; Holograph (Pencil) Originally for organ; arranged by Allen Sigel. The voice part was remarked to be for oboe. (Box 09, Folder 093)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791 Variationen über Unser dummer Pöbel meint; arr. Variations on a theme of Gluck, K. 455, 1986, 1 part (9 p.); Computer-notated score. Originally for piano; arranged for clarinet and piano by Allen Sigel. Part marked for performance by Sigel. Published 1986 by Shall-u-mo Publications, Rochester, New York. (Box 09, Folder 094)
  - Porter, Cole, 1891-1964 Songs. Selections; arr. Cole Porter Medley, undated, 2 manuscript scores and 2 manuscript parts; Pencil holograph score and ink holograph parts. Songs arranged by Allen Sigel for violin, clarinet, and piano. The pencil holograph score includes attached photocopied pages; the pages of the photocopy of the score are numbered 1-33. Accompanied by photocopy of the original version of I love you. (Box 09, Folder 095)
    Contents: It's de-lovely--So in love--My heart belongs to daddy--I love you--You're the top.
  - Porter, Cole, 1891-1964 Cole Porter research folder, undated, 1 folder; Contains manuscript list of recorded Porter songs, 22 leaves of printed Porter lyrics, and photocopies of Porter songs: Always true to you in my fashion, In the still of the night, Just one of those things. (Box 09, Folder 096)
  - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828 Impromptus, piano, no. 4, D.935; arr. Impromptu number 4 in F minor, op. 142, undated, 1 manuscript score (12 p.) and 1 manuscript part (5 p.); Photocopy of holograph score; pencil holograph part. Originally for piano; arranged for clarinet and piano. (Box 10, Folder 097)
  - Turpin, Tom, 1873-1922 Buffalo rag; arr. Buffalo rag (1904), undated, 1 manuscript score (6 p.) and 5 manuscript parts; Holograph (Pencil) Arranged for woodwind quintet. (Box 10, Folder 098)
- Clarinet methods and etudes, 1965-1987, III.; Folder 99-102
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Sigel, Allen Clarinet articulation, 1987, 1 book (76 p.); Published by Roncorp, Inc., Cherry Hill, New Jersey. Musical studies with accompanying text. (Box 10, Folder 099)
  - Sigel, Allen Clarinet masterwork etudes: mastering the masterworks, 1980, 1 book (32 p.); Photocopy of typescript and musical studies based on eleven masterworks of the repertoire for clarinet. Title on cover: Clarinet master class. (Box 10, Folder 100)
  - Sigel, Allen Twentieth century clarinetist, 1965, 1 folder; Combination of mimeographed typescript text and musical etudes written in ink on vellum masters. (Box 10, Folder 101)
  - Sigel, Allen Twentieth century clarinetist, 1965, 1 volume; Spiral-bound volume with 14 preliminary pages of mimeographed text and charts, 49 pages of ozalid reproductions of musical etudes, and 12 pages of mimeographed text following the etudes. (Box 10, Folder 102)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Music--Manuscripts
Genres
Scores